<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../../../rapidminerreferencemanual/documentation2html.xsl"?>
<p1:documents xmlns:p1="http://rapid-i.com/schemas/documentation/reference/1.0"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://rapid-i.com/schemas/documentation/reference/1.0/documentation.xsd">
	<!-- LAST CORRECTIONS: 22/JAN/2014 -->
	<operator key="operator.encryption:pbe_encrypt_file" locale="en"
		version="1.0.000">
		<title>Encrypt File (Password)</title>
		<synopsis>Operator for decrypting password protected files.</synopsis>
		<text>
			<paragraph>This operator expects an password encrypted file as input
				which is then decrypted with the provided password.
			</paragraph>
		</text>
		<inputPorts>
			<port name="file" type="com.rapidminer.operator.nio.file.FileObject">
				The file object which should be
				decrypted. If a file object is connected to this port, the parameter
				'file input' is being ignored.
			</port>
		</inputPorts>
		<outputPorts>
			<port name="file" type="com.rapidminer.operator.nio.file.FileObject">
				The decrypted input file object is
				returned here. If the file output port is
				connected, the parameter
				'file output' is being ignored.
			</port>
		</outputPorts>

		<!-- description of the parameters and the corresponding values -->
		<parameters>
			<parameter key="file_input" type="file">
				Defines the file that
				should be decrypted.
				If a file object is
				connected to the input port
				of the
				operator, this parameter is being ignored.
			</parameter>
			<parameter key="password" type="password">
				The password that should be
				used for file decryption.
			</parameter>
			<parameter key="algorithm_strength" type="selection"
				default="medium">
				This parameter allows you to select the attribute selection filter;
				the method you want to use for selecting attributes. It has the
				following options:
				<values>
					<value value="all">This option simply selects all the attributes of
						the ExampleSet, no attributes are removed. This is the default
						option.
					</value>
					<value value="single">This option allows the selection of a single
						attribute. When this option is selected another parameter
						(attribute) becomes visible in the Parameter View.
					</value>
					<value value="subset">This option allows the selection of multiple
						attributes through a list. All attributes of ExampleSet are
						present in the list; required attributes can be easily selected.
						This option will not work if the meta data is not known. When this
						option is selected another parameter becomes visible in the
						Parameter View.
					</value>
					<value value="regular_expression">This option allows you to specify a regular
						expression for the attribute selection. When this option is
						selected some other parameters (regular expression, use except
						expression) become visible in the Parameter View.
					</value>
					<value value="value_type">
						This option allows selection of all the attributes of a particular
						type. It should be noted that types are hierarchical. For example
						<em>real</em>
						and
						<em>integer</em>
						types both belong to the
						<em>numeric</em>
						type. The user should have a basic understanding of type hierarchy
						when selecting attributes through this option. When this option is
						selected some other parameters (value type, use value type
						exception) become visible in the Parameter View.
					</value>
					<value value="block_type">
						This option is similar in working to the
						<em>value_type</em>
						option. This option allows the selection of all the attributes of
						a particular block type. It should be noted that block types may
						be hierarchical. For example
						<em>value_series_start</em>
						and
						<em>value_series_end</em>
						block types both belong to the
						<em>value_series</em>
						block type. When this option is selected some other parameters
						(block type, use block type exception) become visible in the
						Parameter View.
					</value>
					<value value="no_missing_values">This option simply selects all the attributes of
						the ExampleSet which don&apos;t contain a missing value in any
						example. Attributes that have even a single missing value are
						removed.
					</value>
					<value value="numeric_value_filter">When this option is selected another parameter
						(numeric condition) becomes visible in the Parameter View. All
						numeric attributes whose examples all satisfy the mentioned
						numeric condition are selected. Please note that all nominal
						attributes are also selected irrespective of the given numerical
						condition.
					</value>
				</values>
			</parameter>
			<parameter key="file_output" type="file">
				Defines where the
				decrypted input file should be stored. If the file output
				port is
				connected, the parameter
				'file output' is being ignored.
			</parameter>
			<parameter key="override" type="file">
				The operator does not
				override already existing files by default. If checked an already
				existing file will be overriden without an error.
			</parameter>
		</parameters>

		<relatedDocuments>
			<!-- ... -->
		</relatedDocuments>

		<tutorialProcesses>
			<tutorialProcess
				key="process.select_attributes.select_by_regular_expression"
				title="Selecting attributes by specifying regular expressions matching their names">
				<description>
					<paragraph>
						In the given Example process the Labor-Negotiations ExampleSet is
						loaded using the Retrieve operator. Then Select Attribute operator
						is applied on it. Have a look at the Parameter View of the Select
						Attributes operator. Here is a stepwise explanation of this
						process.
						<ul>
							<li>
								See that at the bottom of Parameters View the
								<em>include special attributes</em>
								parameter is set to true. This means that all special attributes
								will also be checked against all the given conditions, they will
								appear in the output only if they pass all the conditions. The
								only special attribute is the &apos;class&apos; attribute in
								this ExampleSet. Though &apos;class&apos; is a special
								attribute; it will make to the output port only if it passes the
								conditions because the
								<em>include special attributes</em>
								parameter is set to true.
							</li>
							<li>
								The regular expression specified is = w.*|.*y.*
								<ul>
									<li>w.* means all attribute names with starting alphabet
										&apos;w&apos;.</li>
									<li>
										<em>wage-inc-1st, wage-inc-2nd, wage-inc-3rd, working-hours</em>
										satisfy this condition
									</li>
									<li>.*y.* means all attributes that have a &apos;y&apos; in
										their name.</li>
									<li>
										<em>standby-pay, statutory-holidays,
											longterm-disability-assistance</em>
										satisfy this condition.
									</li>
									<li>|| means logical OR operator. So if any attribute whose
										name starts with &apos;w&apos; or its name contains a
										&apos;y&apos;, it satisfies this expression and is selected.</li>
									<li>
										Following attributes of the Labor-Negotiations data set
										satisfy this expression:
										<em>wage-inc-1st, wage-inc-2nd, wage-inc-3rd, working-hours,
											standby-pay, statutory-holidays,
											longterm-disability-assistance</em>
										.
									</li>
								</ul>
							</li>
							<li>
								The
								<em>use except expression</em>
								parameter is also set to true which means attributes that
								satisfy the condition in the
								<em>except regular expression</em>
								parameter would be removed.
								<ul>
									<li>
										The regular expression for
										<em>except regular expression</em>
										is = .*[0-9].*
									</li>
									<li>This expression means any attribute whose name contains a
										digit.</li>
									<li>
										Three attributes satisfy this condition:
										<em>wage-inc-1st, wage-inc-2nd, wage-inc-3rd</em>
										. Thus these three attributes do not make it to the output
										port even though they satisfied the regular expression of the
										<em>regular expression</em>
										parameter.
									</li>
								</ul>
							</li>
							<li>
								Finally we are left with the following four attributes:
								<em>working-hours, standby-pay, statutory-holidays,
									longterm-disability-assistance</em>
								. These four attributes make it to the output port.
							</li>
							<li>
								Notice that the
								<em>invert selection</em>
								parameter was not set to true. If it was set to true, all
								attributes other than these four attributes would have made it
								to the output port.
							</li>
						</ul>
					</paragraph>
					<!-- tutorialProcess description: What is done and shown here? You can 
						use formated text here -->
				</description>
				<!-- Copy process from RapidMiner's XML view to here -->
			</tutorialProcess>
		</tutorialProcesses>
	</operator>
</p1:documents>